hey welcome everyone to the wasabi
research club and this time we still
don't have a vivre but luckily we have
the wonderful David with us who would
like to start this meeting with a joke
let's go hi there thank you for the
introduce I'm I'm embarrassed thank you
so last time you get told that I had the
example with the the cat and the
microwave and there is another story
with Annie as far as I know it may be
just a rumor but did you know why in
America and the car mirror on the left
hand right there is a small text that
the object in the mirror can be closer
than than they are they look like did
you know that there is a text like that
on the mirrors no no it's the same story
as far as I know that okay a guy went to
the court because the mirror you know
it's you know it's not a flat mirror
because you want to see more so it's
it's a bit how do you say that it's it's
not convex
yes it's convex and convex mirrors and
gives the effect that you know that the
object looks closer and they he went to
the court with that and and he won't so
afterwards every mirror car mirror the
manufacturer put this text on the mirror
that the object can be closer so that's
it
[Laughter]
it's similary the cat and the microvia
don't put your get into the microwave
because there was one well one judgment
about this in the past and there they
want to cover their their asses this is
how America works in general this is
also why they label hot drinks like
contents maybe hot or something like
that for every one of those there's a
lawsuit I think the the hot one had to
do with a lady who got like
second-degree burns or something by
spilling coffee on her lap so now every
time you buy a hot drink it says caution
contents may be hot yeah and a bag of
peanuts has a warning about that it
might contain some peanuts let's go into
today's show so you guys who ever missed
last episode you might you I just wanted
to bring bring everyone up to date that
right now we are not reviewing paper but
so we are not a review club club but we
are a research club as the name implies
we are researching now and every week we
are going to talk about our research
progress and just to reiterate the big
picture is that we are looking into
Cohen joins and we are looking into us
to generalize them what's the goal here
is that we want to enable trustless
creation of CO injuries those have not
been enabled in a bird before for
example there was this wonderful enough
sock paper which which would like to
optimize on the number of subsets of
transactions but no one figured out how
to do knapsack mixing
in a trust last way before or blockchain
if you had to share coin implementation
and no one really figured out how do you
do
shared coin style transactions in a
trust last way before and right now we
are working on a solution and hopefully
we will find one actually we found and
thought about one last week and we
talked about a less optimal scheme last
week and right now we have two more
schemes which which we are going to talk
about and let's see what else oh yeah so
but what do we really want to achieve is
that a user could should be able to
register their inputs separately
independently and their outputs
separately independently regardless of
what the input and output desired output
amounts are and that's not and that's
not not an obvious there is an obvious
way to do that and as far as I research
went no one has really figured it out
there where there are some very complex
ecash divisible linkage schemes and what
what some some privacy odd coins are
doing that that could be useful here too
however for coin joints we have a
security guarantee that if a user does
not see his desired output in the final
mix transaction then it's not going to
sign which means we can
make less compromises in our scheme and
hopefully we should be able to come up
with something simpler than let's say
the divisible akash papers are coming up
with and let's go into our very first
protocol which is an ACL based scheme
it's anonymous credentials light is a
paper which we read and modified it in a
way that suits our needs
can I ask someone maybe each time to
screen share here sure
[Music]
yes thank you let's see our mmm we
should talk about it would you like to
go through the high-level scheme
East one or nothing much yeah I mean I
can do it sure
so like last time we were we covered
basically two schemes like one was kind
of broken and the second one was okay we
didn't we didn't really go into the
details but it was a scheme on so it was
a blind signature scheme which allowed
to have blind signature on messages
which are committed in the Patterson
commitment but sadly it's required
pairing base crypto and pairing basic
crypto is a little bit further and far
from what we would like to achieve so
and then I think it was you Val or Adam
who brought this paper into discussion
it was also discussed in the wasabi
research Club two or three weeks ago and
one immediate thing which one needs to
see is that it doesn't require any
pairing base crypto which is nice
because we can just work on on our
regular beloved and sach P 256 K one
curve the high-level picture is
essentially the same we have a nice
commitment scheme which is our beloved
again
Patterson commitment scheme and we can
obtain unlink both blind signatures on
blinded commitments which are which
cannot be linked to the origin also here
we have c1 c2 c3 these are commitments
and we can get from a coordinator from a
server signatures on these Zeta blinded
commitments and so basically this is the
high-level picture and remember we
additionally need to
have this input splitting and output
merging functionalities and this can be
also achieved so this is maybe just the
first high level picture
shall I go into the details or what do
you want to hear about more Lucas just
left and is going to implement it anyway
yeah I just want to clarify that it was
Nick Jonas who brought this paper up to
our attention as far as I know okay all
right I so like we can go into the
details if you want so like in input
registration let's say we shall try do
it should I go yes sure I just wanted to
say that I would like to avoid calling
these blinded commitments and blinded
signatures because if you cut these
blinded that kind of means the server
knows and the user unblind stand which
is not the case these are obtained
signatures for commitments those
correspond to the original commitment
and the server never sees the signatures
and never sees the t's new commitments
but yes they see a scheme actually cause
them blinded anyway yeah go ahead they
the server does see them signature
verification it's just that they're not
linkable to the signing protocol yes
sorry correct so at input registration
it does not see only at output
registration hey guys no power here and
my internet is calm it doesn't want to
come back so I'm just going to go
through the easier based scheme so what
do we have here let's see we want to as
always we want to solve among splitting
amount merging how do we do that well it
turns out if we figure out amount
splitting not exactly correct but in
this case yes then we are going to have
a mount merging to so we start with user
has the UT X so we'd value V so let's
say you have one Bitcoin and you want to
split into outputs with values V 1 and V
2 let's say that zero point four and
zero point six such that V equals V 1
plus V 2 so one Bitcoin equals zero
point four and zero point six this is
splitting and what happens at input
registration user creates and tethers
and commitments c1 equals eveeven r1 or
is the random factor here v1 is of
course the value and we create a number
of pairs and commitments and we say we
have some fake patters and commitments
here from 3 to M which values are 0 and
the V I terms corresponds to single
attribute l0 in the ACS signature with
an empty message with range proofs for
each so anyway this just clarifies the
notation differences between the AC
anonymous credential light paper which
you can see
nevermind so and you also have to prove
the range of each commitments otherwise
you could cheat so it's between 0 and
256 bits or something like that
never minds right proofs this is what
are being used for confidential
transactions to the user also needs to
prove the sum of the commitments of
course the Patterson commitment does
that this is just some concern here that
how to do that you basically prove that
if you give the sum of the or values
because then you will have an equation
like v1 plus v2 plus v3 if it's in a
commitment and with the sum of the
random values then it's going to be then
that's all patters and commitments work
that they are homomorphic so you could
you could have a commitment and prove
that that the the partial commitments
equal to the sum and this is how you
register your inputs so now here is the
non-trivial part and I only understand
the high-level picture here but let's
see from this protocol the user obtains
and signatures for n commitments in a
way where the following properties hold
so the coordinator can be sure that the
the obtained commitments are committing
to the same values as the original
commitments neither the commitments nor
the obtained signatures are known by the
coordinator so this is important because
otherwise it could link
these commitments the original
commitments I and and it just says that
the octane signatures are honorable and
obtained commitments are running cable
to the original commitments so and from
here on it's quite simple at output
registration user can say let's see the
user wants to register 0.4 Bitcoin by
sending the coordinator the obtained
commitment for the 0.4 Bitcoin for vivan
and the DDR value and not quite sure if
this this random value here is the same
as the original commitment maybe
probably I don't know probably this this
this new commitment action not probably
it definitely looks different than the
normal Patterson commitment so just just
keep that in mind and of course you
carriages are some zero commitments
along with the with with the real
commitment with with a commitment that
commits to the to the real value because
the sum will be the same so and of
course you have valid signatures for for
those commitments that you obtained in
at input registration and and that's
pretty much it
here we there is a long conversation
about how many problems this scheme has
but but but it seems like we were able
to to to fix the the problems of this
scheme and in fact
we decided to not go with this anonymous
credentials light based scheme but
probably heat verification anonymous
credential scheme is going to be more
straightforward approach than the ECL
based scheme and this is not quiet
worked out as you can see there are no
not many formulas here that's because we
didn't quite work it out but this seemed
to make sense and this will be the this
will be the topic next in the next was a
B research club and hopefully this will
be the very last scheme that we will go
through because this should solve our
problem in a straightforward non
compromised fake and then we can want to
I am afraid to click on this because I
don't have internet and then we will be
able to move on to to come up with the
next generation mixing technology and
that's it again I'm sorry for the loss
of Internet as a compensation I'm going
to play a bit of VidCon next Hey and
finally the coordinator replies with the
the final message and the user can
finalize their proof that they actually
present during verification and the
paper
nicely replicates the usual Sigma
protocol notation like the first message
a denoted a then E and then the a C and
okay so if the viewer is familiar with
Sigma protocols and illiterate children
can recognize this this pattern by the
way I would strongly recommend to any
wants to read the ACL paper to at least
look at the introduction of a base paper
first because it introduces a lot of
these variable names and it kind of
gives a much clearer intuition for why
the protocol even works and the ACL
paper it's a lot more dense and I mean
since it cites the other paper it kind
of assumes that the intuitions
underlying it yeah so let's talk a
little bit about communication
complexity here so like one thing one
should notice is that this is not just
some hash value which could be obtained
just by naively applying pH a mere
heuristic but this e term has a special
structure so it's it's crafted in a
special way so that's the reason that
the Sigma protocol here cannot be made
just non interactive and this gives us
essentially a five move blind signature
scheme instead of the usual three mode
because the user gives here on the
server the commitment and proof for the
opening of the commitment then the
server replies essentially these two
messages can be sent at once and then
the user needs to reply with this
special value E and just after this
sending this e value can the server send
the final message so this was another
sign for us that we might not want to go
with the with the ACL paper in the fifth
move of course is the signature
verification
yeah and because in current law sabe um
just the chow me I'm blind signature
scheme is just a regular three mo client
signature scheme and obviously overt or
it's it's someone needs to consider also
the communication complexity which is
kind of more we have more happy than
just regular HTTP more to the point it's
prone to failure and failure in this
case like for the round to actually
succeed all of the participants must you
know succeed if any one loser loses
connectivity
everybody has to wait until they come
back or the whole round fails and you
need to basically start over you know
okay so let's finish or is there
anything to add or any questions
regarding the ACL paper yes I just want
to say this sorry guys my internet went
away and of course they're recording but
now I'm recording again and actually I
recorded the whole episode by myself so
anyway I think we are kind of finishing
the ACL paper maybe
now let's enhance and emphasize them why
we are more leaning towards the quack
paper why we are considering that so far
the best scheme we had even though we
didn't manage to fully elaborate on the
coin merging protocol my understanding
is that the quads paper the quads
approach is more straightforward
and it probably requires less
interactivity but correct me if I'm
missing something or if I'm wrong
yeah that's pretty much it so the one
major difference is that these
signatures are only verifiable by the
signer
since it's a Mac it's not a public key
signing scheme this is an algebraic Mac
so unlike triple zero max like H Mac or
whatever it's not built out of hash
functions but out of group operations
and the this makes it so that it's
easier to prove properties about the the
committed values very much like the ACL
scheme the idea is that you have
multiple attributes that the the
signature covers or that the Mac covers
and but because everything is a kind of
simpler it doesn't need to be publicly
verifiable this the whole interaction is
a little bit simpler you only need three
rounds to obtain a credential and then
when you go to present the credential or
sure what credential I think that's the
the name they gave to the algorithm in
the paper you make a zero knowledge
proof that you have a valid Mac on those
values and present randomized
commitments to the same values and the
the server can verify this using their
their secret key there's two variants of
this so the original paper by melissa
chase Sarah Michael John and I always
forget his name I'm sorry introduced a
scheme that attribute can only be filled
values and in that scheme that means
that you need
to have some sort of blind issuance and
the way that they do the blind issuance
is by using el-gamal encryption which is
very similar to Patterson commitments
just with an additional term that makes
it only computationally hiding but it
has like the same nice homomorphic
properties so basically you encrypt your
attributes to yourself you give them to
the server with proofs of their valid
and then you get back a Mac that you can
then decrypt and later use to construct
your proofs when you show this paper
that each one is showing right now is
much more recent paper by Melissa Chase
the third author whose name I forgot and
Trevor Perrin and this is designed for
the bread so this paper what they're
trying to do is solve the problem of
managing who is included in a cinema the
encrypted messaging who's who's a member
of a group in a way that the server
can't really know and the main
difference over the previous paper is
that in this mac scheme the attributes
themselves can be group elements so this
means we can directly use a Patterson
commitment as an attribute and since
those are perfectly hiding that way
if we get it right we can assure that
even if there's a quantum adversary the
coordinator is hacked and somebody
breaks the second P 256k one earth like
worst case scenario
users should still not be d anonymize
about
which seems like a desirable property
for a pro-ball that attempts to improve
on bitcoins privacy problems and other
than that this scheme is very similar to
the other algebraic mark so that that's
the main difference
I guess just thinking out loud like one
would be able to track the coordinator
and get the coordinators Mac secret key
would there be any privacy leak so no
because there know that the coordinator
never sees the actual like the the
values in the at input registration you
never reveal the actual values you'll
name proven zero knowledge that they're
committing to the the right sum and the
the Mac that the coordinator cents to
the user is never presented by the user
to the coordinator instead the user
produces a zero knowledge proof that
they have a valid Mac and that again is
like there's no reliance on
computational hiding there so at least
in theory the coordinator can never be
anonymize and even if the curve is
completely broken what should be lost is
a soundness not not a blindness of this
protocol so I mean at that point it's
kind of all theoretical because bitcoin
is probably gonna be in serious trouble
if anybody can easily solve for discrete
logarithms on the same curve that
Bitcoin uses but let's assume that we
can somehow fix this with you know a
magical soft fork and even if all of the
transcripts that the coordinator saw are
then revealed after the fact
it should be impossible
at least in theory to to link users
input registrations to their output
registrations right I find it funny that
there's a group nameless signal who
basically essentially solved the almost
word by word a very same problem so like
you just need to replace group chats
with coin joins and yeah and then
basically the same problem applies well
actually if you read those parts of the
the paper they have a more serious
challenge to deal with because they need
to like authorized users and D
authorized users and some users are
administrators of groups and then they
need to still have like blind issuance
so to them yeah after a certain point is
just question whether you have one
attribute or two so or or more sorry so
they also make use of the el-gamal
encryption quite heavily and they prove
things about encryptions of user id's
and so on so anyway it's pretty
interesting can you can you elaborate on
the not really a metaphor but what's the
connection between group chat and Cohen
joins so in this original paper they
want to make sure that whenever a user
user wants to send a message in a group
chat the user wants to convince the
server that they are indeed a member of
the specific group chat without without
licking anything about their identity oh
yeah and also the server doesn't
actually know who are the members of any
of the groups right so basically this is
also what what's happening at output
registration phase like word by word
you just need to replace group chats for
coin joints and then yeah it's the same
all right but we are not ready with this
yet as we need to find out the details
but hopefully next week we can also talk
about those details which are missing
right now thank you guys
is there anything else you would like to
go through or say about this okay so we
can talk about a little bit about how we
are hoping to still improve the ISO
scheme as this so we didn't touch upon
the advantages of the quoc approach than
the acs so the main difference here so
in the original algebraic mark paper
things are simplest there as part of the
show protocol the is part of like the
outputs of credential presentation are a
list of commitments to the same
attributes but with different
randomizations and those are just plain
old Paterson commitments the signal
paper so the newer key verifiable and on
the schedules one has a slightly more
complicated if you scroll down you can
see here yeah so M I is the only type of
attribute that we care about so mi is
the original commitment in our case and
Z is a random value that the user
generates so the final commitment that's
presented to the coordinator in this
case is G of Y that's sorry G sub y I
that's a generator for
one of the attributes we only have one
of those sorry we only have two of those
and this reminds me we didn't talk about
double spending so then you rate the the
final commitment here the the Z exponent
only applies to this generator whereas
in the ACL scheme the sort of analogous
gamma term is applied to both the
additional generator and the entire
commitment so it's as if it's G Y I
times a my that entire thing to the
power Z so this makes the equipment
openings a little bit easier to deal
with relative to a CL not as
straightforward as in the original
algebraic Mak paper but they're like the
the attribute values need to be hidden
some other way during issuance okay so
now that I remembered the double
spending a cool aspect of these key
verifiable anomalous credential schemes
compared to anonymous credentials plight
is that it's it supports what's called
an linkable multi show and the idea here
is you have a single credential and you
can present it multiple times and the
individual presentations are unlikable
whereas in the ACL scheme there's a
single signature and that signature
verification action is similar to ECDSA
or noir signatures in that there's like
a hash term so because approach has no
traditional hashing different
presentations are randomized abow very
easily for us it's actually a downside
because this means that a user can
register an input once and then claim it
multiple times and the coordinator would
not know that these two outer
registrations are actually for the same
credential so
complication of these this approach is
that we have to add an additional
attribute for scenario serial number and
that serial number would have to be
revealed as part of out about the
registration and in this way the
coordinator can know that a single
credential is only actually used once I
actually just so I never finished that
point about like why the different
commitment schemes are sorry I am this
is how my brain works so ideally we
would like in both of these schemes to
prove that the some of the credentials
presented the sum of the amounts
committed to buy these credentials
exactly equals the requested output
amount and we have not been able to
figure out a simple zero knowledge proof
to do this for the ACL scheme because of
that pesky gamma term it's absolutely
possible in theory it's just that both
of us are haven't haven't managed to do
that yet so luckily this becomes a
little bit simpler using using this
approach let's put some pressure on us
and and promised the viewers that we
will have the solution by the next
episode definitely two weeks all right
so Lucas are you excited to implement it
yes this can but yes excited to because
I have to read a lot you will learn a
lot in that's good I mean I think that's
the main advantage like
we learned so much along the way so I
think you will enjoy it as well
yes I hope so all right how about you
guys did you understood everything you
always seen Adam that you will only
understand if you if you called it so
I'm not waiting for that point when I
can start holding very true
there's a lovely Python library called a
pet lab privacy enhancing technologies
library it's right it's on github no yes
and on pi PI and this is basically
bindings for open SSL's like a lower
level api's and a petal at P et I don't
know how to spell his name I think da n
easy is then I think with an A initially
but if you just look for pet Lib yes
okay cool so this library has in the
examples directory an implementation of
the ACL signature scheme as well as key
verifiable credentials based on the
original algebraic mac paper so not the
one that we discussed today but the the
older one and both of those rely on this
gens ekp duck pie thing which is I think
it's like a general like the Sigma
protocol based
[Music]
nice where you give like the transcript
in full for both sides and it computes
the actual normal like final proof
values this looks really nice
yeah the code is it's not very
thoroughly commented but it has comments
in all the right places
and I found it very helpful to
understand some of the stuff especially
with the algebraic max scheme and how
the blank Ning works I I didn't
understand that part in the paper
evidently and actually implemented it so
which is the algebra and this is
algebraic man so this is one of the
schemes presented in the original paper
the Mac ggm which has a security proof
only in the generic group model right
for us it doesn't really matter because
we don't super care about soundness we
have that fallback of coin joint
security the other Mac scheme is a
slightly more complicated and only needs
a decisional diffie-hellman for the
security proof and then this like
anonymous credentials construction on
top of it adds all of the like
complicated their knowledge proof stuff
built out of Mac ggm but both algebraic
Mac constructions are possible I don't
actually remember in the signal paper
it's like a variant of Mac ggm with an
additional term T which is part of the
the field and an additional point W
that's part of the secret key and if I'm
not mistaken that addition is what
allowed them to prove it in a nicer
model than the generic group model but
again for our purposes like we fall back
to Bitcoin security first
and hmm this is really nice there's also
I think Isis Lovecraft has an
implementation of the single scheme
already I haven't had time to look into
it yet though all right very good
do you guys have something else to talk
about or should we close this episode
soon before closing please share this
repository
I'm pretty sure you can look at the the
recording and just just see the
repository yes I got it
or you might also put it in the comment
section on YouTube or something like
that
all right so max was everything clear
silence means yes so here thank you guys
thank you guys for de for for two days
today's talk and I hope you enjoyed it
or if not at least learn something and
we will continue towards building better
Bitcoin future without making sure no
one can spy on you alright so thank you
and have a good night bye-bye thank you
thank you bye